Now, run!
Show me you've got spirit!
I think the same thing every time, but...
Come on! Pick up the pace!
This long-distance running
after training sure is rough!
This year's freshmen sure do have potential!
You're embarrassing yourself,
whining like that!
F-Faster again?
I'm about to keel over...
Me too, to be honest!
Looks like you've still got plenty of energy!
Wh-Who has plenty of energy?
That one girl over there...
How much energy does she have?
Well, that's Chris for you...
Reborn
to Master the Blade
From Hero-King to Extraordinary Squire
Episode 8    The Order to Protect Ripple
Those are the upperclassmen.
Seems like it.
Everybody's here, right?
I have very important news for you all!
You'll get the official announcement
at tomorrow's morning assembly,
but we're going to have a guest:
Ripple, the Hyral Menas.
I see. I understand the situation.
A Special-class Rune...
That's Silva Eiren.
The younger brother of Ledas Eiren,
head of the Royal Guard,
and the only Special-class
Rune bearer at the academy.
We are to protect Ripple and eliminate
any magicite beasts that appear,
while ensuring that nothing in the
vicinity is damaged. Correct?
Correct!
We can't predict when Ripple's
condition will strike,
or when the magicite beasts will appear.
Sorry for the trouble, everyone.
So he's the strongest
student at the academy.
That's great. I'd love to fight him!
That's all you ever think about.
You've all been specially
chosen from your grades.
Each grade's members will form a team,
and each team will take turns
protecting Ripple for a day.
Please isolate the magicite beasts
from the surrounding area
using a barrier generated by these Artifacts
before attempting to eliminate them.
We ask that you have someone who can create
a barrier by Ripple's side at all times.
I don't see a bow.
I can't use any of these.
I guess I'll take one.
If I transform my aether into mana,
I might be able to generate a barrier.
There's no point in giving you that.
A Runeless squire can't use
one of those things.
Keep your hands off them.
Okay, got it!
Wait! You don't need to—
Rani, it's fine.
What's a squire doing here, anyway?
Having a Runeless here
just puts the rest of us at risk.
Leave, now.
Good grief. He's the highly strung,
short-tempered type, right?
And not just the squire.
We also have a traitor's
blood relative in our midst.
I can't entrust my life
to the sister of the traitor Leon.
Leone and Leon are different people.
Even as an upperclassman,
you can't talk to her like that!
That's right!
That's such a shallow thing to think!
When you get to know her, you'll understand.
What?
No fighting, okay?
Silva, I think that remark
went a little far...
In that case, Upperclassman Silva...
How about determining our worthiness
for the mission first-hand through battle?
A battle? Between you people and me?
Excuse me.
I don't want to. I don't care enough.
And if the squires are supposed to leave...
then I'm a squire, so I'm leaving.
Wait, Yua!
What?
I'm sleepy.
Did you hear what I said?
I need your help.
Tee-hee.
It's hard to discern exactly
what that "tee-hee" means.
You're the best student in the second year!
We need you here!
That's right, Yua!
I don't know if we're strong
enough to do this without you!
Okay.
I'll do it.
Okay, Yua. Let's all fight Silva together—
No.
So you lack the courage to face me, then.
I already know who's stronger.
I don't like bullying the weak.
What?
Principal, did those two...
Yes, they had a mock battle one time...
Yua, you can't say that to his face!
And Yua won?
First he wants me to leave,
then he wants a duel.
Yes. Ever since then,
they've been like oil and water.
He's a pain in the butt.
As the strongest of the freshmen,
I'm not the one who proposed a battle.
it'd be a huge help if you could get
them to see eye to eye again...
If you want me to beat the both
of them at once, I'd be happy to!
I'm sorry, everyone.
This is my fault.
I'm causing problems for you all...
Ripple...
Ripple?!
Wh-What?
Be careful, everyone!
Theodore, get away from here!
I'll put up a barrier! Be careful!
Here they come!
Ma'am, who's in charge today?
May we third-year students
have the first day?
That's fine by me...
Magicite beasts!
They're demihuman!
You all heard the principal.
Nobody but us third-years
can lay a hand on them—
You there!
I just said you can't lay a hand on them!
I know!
That's why I used my foot!
That girl's a squire, but she's so strong!
I can see why they called her here!
And...
She's so cute!
We've got more important
things to think about now!
Everyone in my grade, fight!
No amount of physical damage
will hurt a magicite beast!
A gun Artifact? That's a rare sight.
Let's see what he's capable—
Rani!
Don't come running to me
if he gets mad at you!
But I didn't lay a hand on them!
I shot them with my bow.
Oh! That's fine, then!
That's not what I meant!
You can't selfishly—
Who's being selfish?
Ripple's going to suffer if someone
here gets hurt, no matter who it is!
Your pride isn't what matters here!
We all need to work together!
What? You don't have a Special-class Rune.
You don't have the right—
I've seen someone who does up close!
You're going to be a holy knight and
fight alongside a Hyral Menas, right?
Then you should try to be more
understanding of her than anyone here!
When she believes in something,
she won't back down,
no matter who she's talking to.
That's the spirit!
Silva! More incoming!
All right! Third-years, engage the enemy!
I just happened to swing my spear,
and it hit the enemy!
And I guess my sword collided
with something! Sorry!
Why are you all like this?
Now, now, Silva!
Let's say it's the principal's orders!
Everybody, engage the enemy!
I'll do my best!
Yua!
You heard what she said, right?
Don't be upset! Help fight!
I'm sorry!
Smack.
Wow!
I may be under increased gravity right now,
but this is the first time
anyone's been faster than me.
Sorry.
It's fine!
Nice.
Thank you! I'd love to battle you sometime!
I'd rather not.
I don't want to compare my
strength with other people.
Aww, come on!
No.
Please!
Not a chance.
I'm begging you!
Wow, those two are incredible.
Never.
Please!
This is so easy.
No way.
Stop gawking and fight!
That should do it.
Ripple!
If it's the same as it was before,
she should wake up soon.
Good work, everyone.
But this is only a way to keep the damage
to a minimum, and not a solution.
Do you have a solution?
It's going to take time,
but we'll do our best.
I would appreciate it if you would!
I don't know how much of this
the school building can take.
That's your fault!
For not watching where you
were hitting the enemy!
We held back as best we could...
Right? Um...
My name's Inglis, Yua!
In... Ingl... In...
Yua's not good at learning people's names.
That's right, Bean Sprout.
See? She's known me for a year.
The name's Morris, by the way.
Nice to meet you.
Call me what you like, then, Yua!
Okay, then...
You can be Boobs.
And if the upperclassmen had worked harder,
we wouldn't have needed to do all that.
I was just holding back so that my Artifact
wouldn't destroy the building!
Think when you fight!
We were thinking, right, Boobs?
When I became king of an entire country,
I never thought the day would
come when I'd be called "Boobs."
You never know what
fate's got in store for you.
And that's what she decided
to call you, Inglis?
It's embarrassing.
She didn't bother to learn my name either.
What did she call you?
"Lady Animal Ears."
It doesn't bother me.
What did she call you, Rafinha?
"Little Devil."
That thunder she brought down
must've really scared her...
I don't think it's fair.
And Leone?
"Boobs #2."
"Two" for short.
And you, Liselotte?
C... "Curly Hair."
Man, that sucks for all you guys!
I'm more upset with Silva!
What was his problem?
He's so arrogant and nasty!
He's a little wound up.
But I think he'd be a good match for me.
Checkmate.
I-I lose.
Chris is always good at whatever she does.
Checkmate.
I lose again...
Would you like to play a game, Ripple?
Nah, I'm not really into this stuff.
I'm more of the physical type.
How about a battle, then?
A bit of exercise is good for the mind, too!
Chris, we're here to protect Ripple!
That's right. You're supposed
to defend her, not fight her!
Sure.
Yeah, let's do it.
R-Really?
Miliera and Theodore were saying they
wanted to see what happens when I fight.
And I want to see your
strength for myself, too.
Wow, you sure look pleased!
Well, I assumed you'd say that eventually.
You know your students well, then.
In that case, can we get started right away?
Theodore, give it to her.
Leone, here.
It's the same shape as Leone's sword.
What's this?
A Greater Artifact.
After the battle with the
magicite beasts yesterday,
it seemed safer to move them somewhere
else than put up a barrier.
So I asked Theodore for it.
Its Gift moves everyone in its vicinity
into a pocket space, isolating them.
That's amazing!
Leone's Rune is the most compatible
with it in terms of element.
Mine?
We'd like you to test how strong
the space is and how long it holds.
So please conduct your battle
within the effect of this Artifact.
If it works, we can share it
with the other teams.
Okay, Leone. Do it right now! Now! Now!
She can't wait to fight, can she?
Go ahead.
We'd like to see how it
works from inside, too.
Okay, then. Let's see...
Focus your mind.
Leone, you can do it!
You don't need to force it.
Just give yourself over to
the flow the Rune creates...
Okay...
Yes, just like that...
I did it!
It's like the Labyrinth of Trials...
You okay, Leone? You feeling all right?
I-I'm okay.
You can start.
Thanks!
Let's do this, Ripple!
Yeah!
It's been so long since
I last fought a Hyral Menas.
I can barely contain my excitement!
Miliera, block any stray shots, okay?
Okay!
Start light and gradually ramp it up, okay?
Roger.
Come on, then.
Here I go!
A head-on fight!
Nice punch!
M-My goodness.
Inglis is attacking with incredible speed.
But Ripple's dodging it all easily!
That was a little close!
I'll do this my usual way, then.
Close-up fighting isn't my style.
A gun?
Now I understand why you said
Silva would be a good match for you.
Yup.
Here I go.
An ice blade!
I made an ice blade with magic! It worked!
If I'd waited until the last second to dodge,
I wouldn't have given her that opening.
Nice. Here I go!
I'll address that next time.
Oh, no!
I can handle this much.
Nothing stronger, though!
That means I can give it my all!
Please listen to what I'm saying!
I need to get close and take the offensive!
Ripple's strength is her ability
to keep her distance at all times.
I need to overcome that and win!
They're getting closer!
Inglis is trying to get
close enough to attack!
I'm not going to stop moving.
I'll catch up to you!
You look so happy!
If I can get one step closer,
she'll be in range!
Another gun?
Yup. Dual handguns.
There!
I'm not done yet!
Now it's my turn to go on the offensive.
Can you get close to me?
I can't see an opening from either of them!
Chris!
What do I do?
Wait for her to run out of ammo?
Or will my stamina run out first?
She's not moving?
So that's it.
I'm fighting at her range,
which means I'm moving and she's not.
So maybe...
If I turn toward her and become
a smaller target...
The bullets will have to be closer together!
Got you!
Take this!
There's my opening!
She'll hit them!
Are you okay?
Oww...
You not only deflected my bullets,
you threw them back at me?
Are you some kind of pervert?
Miliera, thanks for catching me
with your barrier.
No, I didn't do anything.
I thought you were going to slam into it,
but when you touched the barrier,
it disappeared like it had been sucked away.
You mean your mana was drained away?
Um, can we continue?
Can we test that with
someone else's Artifact?
You can use mine.
Um, our fight...
Chris!
They're having a serious conversation!
Touch this, Ripple.
Does anything feel strange?
Nothing.
Miliera, now you borrow her Artifact.
The angel wings?
I'm a little old for those...
Go ahead, Ripple.
It's absorbing her mana,
just like we thought.
But only Miliera's!
Maybe it's because Hyral Menases
can only take power
from a holy knight with a Special-class Rune?
Yes. The weapon transformation power,
which normally requires intent on her part
and the power of a Special Rune, has been
twisted into absorbing mana on its own.
And when a certain amount
has been absorbed...
It summons magicite beasts.
Sorry, Inglis.
Take care of them for me...
Ripple!
I-I'm sorry!
I can't keep this up anymore!
m 0 0 l 100 0 100 100 0 100
Your
nickname
can be...
m 0 0 l 100 0 100 100 0 100
"Principal
Who's
Trying
To
Look
Young"
Comic by Kuromura Moto